[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：最后，
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Finally,
关于生活在浏览器中的另一件事是分工的问题。
one more thing about living in the browser is a problem of division in labor.
因为我们现在正在做客户端服务器编程，对于一些工作的人来说
Cuz we're now doing client server programming, and for some people working
在浏览器中，这是第一次进行客户端服务器编程。
in the browser this is the first time to be doing client server programming.
这意味着您正在编写分布式应用程序，其中一半的应用程序
And that means you're writing distributed application where half of the application
在一台机器上运行，而一半的应用程序在另一台机器上运行。
is running in one machine and half of the applications running in another machine.
你如何分配工作，如何决定什么进入哪台机器？
How do you divide the work, how you decide what goes in which machine?
我看到人们在每一个可能的维度上都会犯错误。
And I've seen people make mistakes in every possible dimension.
例如，在Web的早期，所有东西都在服务器中。
For example, early on in the web everything was in the server.
浏览器被视为终端，特别是IBM3270终端。
The browser was treated as a terminal, specifically as an IBM 3270 terminal.
您将向服务器发送信息，并且
And you would send information to the server, and
服务器将生成新视图并将其发送出去。
the server would generate a new view and send it out.
这是非常低效的，而且
And that was hugely inefficient, and
正是由于认识到了这种低效，Ajax才变得如此受欢迎。
it was recognition of that inefficiency which got the Ajax thing so popular.
所以当Ajax开始时，它走了另一条路。
So when Ajax started, it went the other way.
人们开始将整个应用程序放在浏览器中
People started putting the entire application in the browser and
他们将服务器视为文件系统。
they were treating the server as a file system.
我看到人们试图基本上在浏览器中复制他们的数据库。
And I saw people trying to basically replicate their database in the browser.
他们会说拿走我们所有的东西，因为谁知道我们是否需要它，而且
They'd say take everything we got cuz who knows if we need it or not, and
他们会把所有东西都送过来。
they'd send everything over.
然后他们会抱怨，为什么要花这么长时间来发送所有的数据？
And then they'd complain well, why does it takes so long to send all that data?
事实证明，这也不是一个好的做法。
That turns out not to be a good way to do it either.
那么正确的方法是什么？
So what's the right way?
这是为了寻求中庸之道。
It's to seek the middle way.
您希望在专业对等体之间创建愉快的对话，
That you want to create a pleasant dialog between specialized peers,
你想最大限度地减少流量，
you want to minimize the volume of traffic,
你想要在及时的基础上发送东西。
you want to be sending stuff on a just in time basis.
您不需要向浏览器发送它可能需要知道的所有内容，
You don't need to send the browser everything it might ever need to know,
你只需要发送它下一步需要的东西。
you just need to send it what it needs next.
这通常是一组小得多的数据，一些你可以发送的东西，
And that's usually a much smaller set of data, something you can send very,
速度非常快，特别是我们的网络已经变得如此
very quickly, particularly as our networks have gotten so
表演者。&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：和
performant. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: And
这就是浏览器的结束。
that's the end of the browser.
有什么问题吗？
Any questions about that?
是啊。&gt；&gt；演讲者2：我只是好奇你的
Yeah. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: I'm just curious what your
思想是，一种虚拟DOM方法，像Diffing，和
thoughts are, kind of the virtual DOM approach, like diffing, and
我不知道你有没有什么意见，或者。&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：是的，
I don't know if you have any opinions, or. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yeah,
我有意见，我不知道他们是不是有用的意见。
I got opinions, I don't know if they're useful opinions.
所以一般来说，DOM是一个可怕的模型。
So generally the DOM is a horrible model.
并将这种可怕的东西传播到网络的另一边，
And propagating that horribleness onto the other side of the network,
我认为这只会让你在那个糟糕的模式中停留更长时间。
I think just keeps you stuck in that awful model for longer.
我希望有一天我们能找到把自己从DOM中解放出来的方法，
I'm hoping someday we figure out a way to liberate ourselves from the DOM,
因为它真的很可怕。
cuz it really is dreadful.
关于图书馆，让我感到鼓舞的是
And the thing that's encouraging to me about the library is
他们提供了一种方法来做到这一点。
that they provide a way of doing that.
例如，jQuery作为
That, for example, jQuery is so much superior as an API for
将页面上的图形元素寻址到DOM提供的内容。
addressing graphical elements on a page to what the DOM provides.
我希望看到我们在那个维度上变得更好。
I'd like to see us get better in that dimension.
&gt；&gt；Speaker 3：jQuery只是一个包装器吗
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Is the jQuery just a wrapper
在DOM周围？
around the DOM?
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：是的。&gt；&gt；扬声器3：好的。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: It is. &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Okay.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：但事实证明你
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: But it turns out you
不需要太多的包装就可以使DOM明显更好。
don't need much wrappage to make the DOM significantly better.
DOM太可怕了，我建议不要使用我展示的任何东西
The DOM is so horrible, I recommend don't use anything that I've showed
你在最后一个小时，什么都不要用。&gt；&gt；扬声器3：不要使用
you in the last hour, don't use anything. &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Don't use
getElementById，只是使用jQuery？&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：找到一些库，
getElementById ever, just use jQuery? &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Find some library,
我并不是一定要推荐jQuery。&gt；&gt；扬声器3：好的。
I'm not recommending jQuery necessarily. &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Okay.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：但是有些图书馆，
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: But some library,
每个库都比DOM好，我很高兴这样说。
every library is better than the DOM, I'm happy to say that.
甚至，我也不知道外面最糟糕的图书馆是什么，但不管它是什么，
Even, I don't know what the worst library out there is, but whatever it is,
它不可能有DOM一半的糟糕。&gt；&gt；扬声器3：如何可以，
it can't be half as bad as the DOM is. &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: How can,
如果jQuery只是调用getElementById，如何能够
if jQuery just calls getElementById, how can
使用jQuery CSS比Get更好。&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：它是
using a jQuery CSS be better than get on. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: It's
为你隐藏那些东西，它增加了一个抽象的层次。
hiding that stuff for you, it's adding a level of abstraction.
它在方向上增加的足够多，所以
It's adding enough in direction so
您不是从DOM的角度思考，而是更多地在
you're not thinking in terms of what the DOM does, you're thinking more in
你需要做什么的条款。
terms of what you need to do.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：好的。&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：和
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Okay. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: And
这是非常有效的。
it's very effective at that.
很多其他的图书馆也是。&gt；&gt；演讲者3：好的，那么，另一个问题。
A lot of other libraries are too. &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Okay so, other question.
我有点认为DOM就是浏览器。
I kind of thought that the DOM was the browser.
没有DOM浏览器如何工作？
How'd the browser work without a DOM?
因为你说有HTML，然后就在
Because you said there was HTML, and then right around
在HTML从全部大写变为小写的同时，DOM被发明了。
the same time that HTML was going from all caps to lowercase, the DOM was invented.
你怎么会有一个没有DOM的浏览器呢？
How would you have a browser without a DOM?
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：在有之前
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Before there was
JavaScript没有必要
JavaScript there was no need for
一个DOM，对吗？&gt；&gt；扬声器3：没有建模
a DOM, right? &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: There was no modeling of
DOM，但DOM存在于某些-&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：浏览器
the DOM, but the DOM existed in some- &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: The browser
有一棵树，但它没有用于
had a tree, but it had no API for
才能访问该树。&GT；&GT；扬声器3：好的，
the to get access to that tree. &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Okay,
好吧。&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：什么事？
all right. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yes?
&gt；&gt；扬声器4：我想只是在听
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: I guess listening to just
一切的历史，这可能不是一个问题。
the history of everything, and it might not be a question.
但是什么，所有的东西都变成了现在的样子。
But what, everything is funneled into what it is right now.
而且看起来事情以一种非常简洁的方式非常稳定地进行着。
And it seems like things are pretty stably moving in a very succinct way.
然后当我听到你的故事说这个是怎么来的，这个来了
And then when I listen to your stories of how this came from this, and this came
从这里，所有这些语言都来自其他所有的语言。
from this, and all these languages came from all of these other languages.
你有没有意见或者回答为什么这么一分钟，
Do you have an opinion or an answer to why such a minute,
为什么每件事都这么专注？
how come everything is focused so much?
为什么没有这么多这些不同想法的发展呢？
How come there isn’t so much of this development of these different ideas?
当你说有一个想法的时候，
When you were saying the idea of having a,
返回一个函数花了很多年才弄明白这一点。
returning a function took years to figure that out.
为什么，还在继续吗，到底是怎么回事，
Why, is that still going on, and what's going on with that,
为什么会减速？&GT；&GT；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：一直都是
why the slowdown? &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: It has always been
慢点，我们第三天再谈这个。
slow, we'll talk about this on the third day.
我们认为自己是最具创新性的行业，
We think of ourselves as being the most innovative of industries,
也许我们是。
and maybe we are.
但我们也是人类
But we're also humans and
人类倾向于极端厌恶变化。
humans tend to be extremely change averse.
最后认识到新的价值的人
And the people who are the last to recognize the value of a new
技术往往是最能从中受益的人。
technology are often the people who would most benefit from it.
在软件技术中有很多这样的例子
And there are lots of examples of that in software technology and
然后我们会看看这些。
then we will look at those.